<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Authentication on Notes</title><link>https://abskmj.github.io/notes/tags/authentication/</link><description>Recent content in Authentication on Notes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>&amp;copy; abskmj</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 10:41:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://abskmj.github.io/notes/tags/authentication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Authenticate REST APIs using JWT</title><link>https://abskmj.github.io/notes/posts/topics/rest-api/authentication-jwt-rest-apis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 10:41:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://abskmj.github.io/notes/posts/topics/rest-api/authentication-jwt-rest-apis/</guid><description>Authentication vs Authorization Authentication: identifying the user who is accessing the resource Authorization: checking if the user has permission to perform an action on the resource (e.</description><content>&lt;h1 id="authentication-vs-authorization">Authentication vs Authorization&lt;/h1>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Authentication: identifying the user who is accessing the resource&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Authorization: checking if the user has permission to perform an action on the resource (e.g updating the resource)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h1 id="jwt-for-authentication">JWT for Authentication&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>JWT or JSON Web Token is a preferrable method for authenticating REST APIs because:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>A datastore is not required for its verification.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It can be issued and verified by a specific application server which has access to the &lt;code>secret&lt;/code> key.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It has placeholder for additional data whose integrity can be validated.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It has an expiry time associated with it.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>JWT can be passed in the &lt;code>Authorization&lt;/code> header.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="jwt-not-for-authorization">JWT not for Authorization&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>The data placeholder in JWT makes it a candidate for authorization as well. Server can put roles/grants information in it. However, it is not recommended to be used because:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>It is difficult to update a JWT.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It is difficult to revoke a JWT.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Any changes to JWT is not real-time as each has a specified time of expiry before which it is treated as valid by the application server.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>