<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Node.js on console.log(&#39;Hello World!&#39;);</title>
    <link>http://clog.logicize.co/tags/node.js/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Node.js on console.log(&#39;Hello World!&#39;);</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2017 abskmj</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 09:56:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://clog.logicize.co/tags/node.js/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploy functions on Spotinst using Serverless Framework</title>
      <link>http://clog.logicize.co/posts/tutorials/spotinst/serverless-spotinst-setup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jan 2019 09:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://clog.logicize.co/posts/tutorials/spotinst/serverless-spotinst-setup/</guid>
      <description>Spotinst is one of the providers which support deploying serverless functions or FaaS (Function as a Service). Serverless Framework is an NPM module which makes building serverless applications easy and open.
Isolated Workspace The steps listed below is different from the traditional steps listed on the official site. I always like to keep all the NPM modules and related files within the project directory to keep things isolated from other projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing an Angular project on Cloud9 IDE</title>
      <link>http://clog.logicize.co/posts/tutorials/cloud9/angular-project-cloud9-ide/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:46:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://clog.logicize.co/posts/tutorials/cloud9/angular-project-cloud9-ide/</guid>
      <description>Update NodeJS version  All of the blank VMs on cloud9 have nvm pre installed. List all the available versions from the official site.  nvm ls-remote  Choose to install the latest version  nvm install v10.6.0  Choose to use the latest version  nvm use v10.6.0  Check the version in use  node --version Angular  Install latest Angular CLI package  npm install -g @angular/cli  Create a new project named my-project (you can use any name you need)  ng new my-project cd my-project  Change start script in package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Track API usage with Google Analytics</title>
      <link>http://clog.logicize.co/posts/tutorials/track-api-usage-google-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 18:02:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://clog.logicize.co/posts/tutorials/track-api-usage-google-analytics/</guid>
      <description>Google analytics is a popular tool to track your website usage. Usage of server APIs can also be tracked with this tool. Measurement Protocol APIs can be used to post the usage data to Google Analytics.
 Measurement Protocol can be used to track user interactions in any environment of internet connected devices. It allows developers to collect user-interaction in form of event or hit.
 API Hit Each invocation of an API can be tracked as a unique event.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>